Guide to the Richard P. Heitzenrater Papers, 1956-2007.
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Richard P. Heitzenrater papers 1956-2007
University Archives, Duke University
Heitzenrater, Richard P.
17.0 Linear Feet 300 Items
Richard Paul Heitzenrater was born in 1939 and lived in New York until coming to Duke University in 1957. He graduated in 1961 with a degree in History and went on to earn a degree in Church History (1964) as well as a Ph.D. in Religion, History (1972) both from Duke.
The collection contains posters, Christmas cards, brochures, and numerous other printed documents showcasing Heitzenrater's graphic design. The collection also contains DVDs which were produced and edited by Heitzenrater.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Originals of video and audiotapes are closed to use. Patrons must request use copies to access the content of the material.
Provenance
The Richard P. Heitzenrater Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in August 28, 1964, August 27, 1969 and November 21, 2007.
Biographical Note
Richard Paul Heitzenrater entered Duke University in 1957. He graduated in 1961 with a degree in History and went on to earn a degree in Church History (1964) as well as a Ph.D. in Religion, History (1972) both from Duke. After earning his degrees Heitzenrater worked as an Associate Pastor at First United Methodist Church in Butler, Pennsylvania and held teaching jobs at Centre College as well as Southern Methodist University. In 1993 Heitzenrater returned to Duke and has since held the position of William Kellon Quick Professor of Church History and Wesley Studies. He has authored a number of books and is regarded as preeminent scholar on the life of John Wesley. However, Heitzenrater has been involved with much more than just academics while here at Duke. He is a gifted graphic artist and has created Christmas cards, event posters (with his brother Drew Heitzenrater), brochures, and various other printed materials. He also sings with the Duke Chapel Choir and has produced a number of DVDs documenting their performances.
Collection Overview
The collection contains posters, Christmas cards, brochures, and numerous other printed documents showcasing Heitzenrater's graphic design. The collection also contains DVDs of the Duke University Choir Chapel tours which were produced and edited by Heitzenrater.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Chapel Choir.
Graphic arts
Heitzenrater, Richard P.
Heitzenrater, W. Drew
Christmas cards
DVDs
Posters
Related Material
Inventory of the Biographical Reference Collection, 1972-2004.
University Archives, Duke University.
Inventory of the News Service Biographical Files, circa 1930s-2004.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Richard P. Heitzenrater Papers, 1956-2007, 10 Boxes
  The poster designs are from various divisions of the University and were created by Richard P. Heitzenrater and his brother W. Drew Heitzenrater.
  - Poster Designs, 1956-1969 (folders 1-4) (Box 1)
  - Poster Designs, 1956-1969 (folders 5-8) (Box 2)
  - Poster Designs, 1956-1969 (folders 9-12) (Box 3)
  - Poster Designs, 1956-1969 (folders 13-16) (Box 4)
  - Poster Designs, 1956-1969 (folders 17-20) (Box 5)
  - Poster Designs, 1956-1969 (folders 21-24) (Box 6)
  - Poster Designs, 1956-1969 (folders 25-27) (Box 7)
  - Bracey's Design Printing, Richard Heitzenrater (Box 8 (formerly box 3))
  - Christmas Cards
  - Contact sheets, Christmas cards
  - Contact Sheets, posters
  - Reports, Medical Research at Duke, Decade for Decision
  - Reports, Program of Capital Expansion, Duke University Divinity School
  - Small Posters (3)
  - DVD Collection (Box 9 (formerly box 4))
    - Duke University Chapel Choir, England Tour, 1995
    - Duke University Chapel Choir, England Tour, 1995 and China Tour, 1997
    - Duke University Chapel Choir, China Tour, 1997
    - The Organs of Duke Chapel, 1997
    - Duke University Chapel Choir, Gala Concert, 1999
    - Duke University Choral Activities, The Year of Music, 1999
    - Duke University Chapel Choir, Year of Music Gala Concert Rehearsal, 2004
    - Duke University Chapel Choir in Spain, 2006
    - Duke University Chapel Choir, The Year of Music, undated
  - Christmas cards created by Heitzenrater as well as files on their production. Also a binder documenting the history of the Divinity School governance, 1962-1971. (Box 10 (formerly Box 5))